The world will never be the same once you've seen it
through the eyes of Forrest Gump.
Forrest Gump is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
A man with a low IQ has accomplished great things in his life and been present during
significant historic events—in each case, far exceeding what anyone imagined he could do.
But despite all he has achieved, his one true love eludes him.
Forrest Gump, played by Tom Hanks.
Jenny Curran, played by Robin Wright.
Lieutenant Dan Taylor, played by Gary Sinise.
Mrs. Gump, played by Sally Field.
Bubba Blue, played by Mykelti Williamson.
Young Forrest Gump, played by Michael Conner Humphreys.
Forrest Gump is a 1994 American comedy-drama film directed by Robert Zemeckis.
An adaptation of the 1986 novel by Winston Groom, the
film's screenplay was written by Eric Roth.
It stars Tom Hanks in the title role, alongside Robin Wright, Gary
Sinise, Mykelti Williamson, and Sally Field in lead roles.
The film follows the life of an Alabama man named Forrest Gump (Hanks)
and his experiences in the 20th-century United States.
Principal photography took place between August and December 1993,
mainly in Georgia, North Carolina, and South Carolina.
Extensive visual effects were used to incorporate Hanks into
archived footage and to develop other scenes.
The soundtrack features songs reflecting the different periods seen in the film.
Various interpretations have been made of the
protagonist and the film's political symbolism.
Forrest Gump was released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on July 6, 1994, and received widespread critical acclaim for Zemeckis's direction, the
performances (particularly those of Hanks and Sinise), story, writing, emotional weight, visual effects, music, character development and screenplay.
The film was a major success at the box office: it became the top-grossing film in the United States released that year and earned over US$678.2 million
worldwide against a $55 million budget during its theatrical run, making it the second-highest-grossing film of 1994, behind The Lion King.
The soundtrack sold over 12 million copies.
Forrest Gump is often regarded as one of the greatest and most influential films ever made, and won six Academy Awards: Best
Picture, Best Director, Best Actor for Hanks, Best Adapted Screenplay, Best Visual Effects, and Best Film Editing.
It received many award nominations, including Golden Globes, British
Academy Film Awards, and Screen Actors Guild Awards.
In 2011, the Library of Congress selected the film for preservation in the United States National
Film Registry as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".
The film explores themes of new year's eve, vietnam war,
vietnam veteran, mentally disabled, friendship.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.